now I want to look at an example where
this vacuously true part applies
vacuously true meant that when the
hypothesis was false so it didn't even
get off the ground then we were going to
still say that the true the statement is
true but but true in a sort of
unimportant or or uninteresting or
vacuous sense so consider this statement
if Trevor is a unicorn then everyone
gets an A in the class so it is set up
this this is an if P then Q I can say
this is an if
P then Q statement or alternatively I
can say it is a p implies Q
statement now what we know is that
because I can turn a conditional like
this into a disjunctive into an or
statement of the form not P or Q let me
try to rewrite this in that form so in
this statement what I've said is either
Trevor is not unicorn so this is the
statement not P
now or everyone gets an a that's the
same statement I had before that is
again
Q when it's written in this form however
when it's written in its disjunctive
form I think it's more obvious that we
should say that that is true either
Trevor is not a unicorn or everyone gets
an a one of those two things is true it
turns out to be unfortunately the uh
Trevor is not a unicorn one however we
still have this logical form that is is
equivalent to the first one that's
written in its conditional or
implication form and it's because of
examples like this that we say that it's
vacuously true yes this statement down
here is true uh one of these two things
in myor statement is true the Trevor is
not a unicorn but it's not interesting
that it's not an important conclusion
the statement doesn't really mean
anything I can say anything I want here
if pigs fly then you get a million bucks
uh all of these statements are sort of
true but true in a vacuous sets